Guide to the Allan R. Holmberg collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966.
Holmberg, Allan R., collection on Peru, circa 1946-1966
- Series I. Cornell Peru Project (Accession 1)
  - Administrative Materials
    - Administrative Correspondence
      - Correspondence Between Vicos Field Station and Outside Individuals or Organizations
        - a. G b. field note books, expense arrangements of Cornell Peru Project--Methodology Project, data processing, New Seed Potato analysis--critique, water pump maintenance, photographic study c. Ghersi Barrera, Humberto; Blanchard, William C.; Goldsen, Rose K.; Guillen, Abraham e. Instituto de Estudios Etnologicos, Cornell Methodology Project, Cornell Peru Project, Gross Equipment S.A. f. correspondence, reports, balance sheets, receipts, telegrams, lists g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - a. H, I, K b. generator maintenance, hacienda lease, information request, services rendered to project, school children art projects, visitors to Vicos c. Blanchard, William C.; Holmberg, Allan R.; Kauffman Doig, Federico; Kedney, May; Kennedy, John e. Homelite Corporation, Cornell Peru Project, Sociedad Publica de Beneficencia de Huaraz f. correspondence, notes, receipts, report g. Port Chester, NY, USA; Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Saratoga Springs, NY, USA; Lima, Peru (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - a. L, M b. shipments to USA--personal, hacienda administration, cow theft arbitration, generator and water pump installation, project financial account, army reservists, visitors to Vicos, information request, public health studies, Vicos school arrangements c. Blanchard, William C.; Luna G., Samuel; Leon Herrera, Celso; Luna Egusquiza, Enrique T.; MacFadden, Arthur R.; Mangin, William; Montalvo Vidal, Abner e. Cerro de Pasco Corp., Ministerio de Educacion Publica, Cornell Peru Project f. correspondence, telegrams, program g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; Carhuaz, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - a. N b. project financial account, anthropometric study, visitors to Vicos c. Holmberg, Allan R.; Newman, Marshall T.; Blanchard, William C.; Collazos Chiriboga, Carlos e. Servicio Cooperativo Inter-Americano de Salud Publica, The National City Bank of New York, Smithsonian Institution, Cornell Peru Project f. correspondence, bank statements, reports g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; Washington, D.C., USA, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - a. 0, P b. generator and water pump maintenance, financial account, medical survey, public health program c. Blanchard, William C.; Ortiz Vergara, Pedro; Patch, Richard W.; Coleto, Delfin; Ponce de Leon, Juan; Campos Sanchez, Manuel; Ramos C., Nilo; Villa Crespo, Moises e. D.W. Onan and Sons Inc.; Peerless Pump Division; Proyecto Programa Pativilca--Huarez--Huaylas del Ministerio de Salud; Ministerio de Salud Publica y Asistencia Social f. correspondence, telegrams, receipts g. Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA; Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; Los Angeles, Calif., USA; Huarez, Ancash, Peru, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - a. R b. customs arrangements, visitors to Vicos, data processing c. Blanchard, William C.; Reyes Coz, Jorge; Roos, Charles F.; Ryan, Bryce e. Econometric Institute, Inc., Cornell Peru Project f. correspondence, telegram g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; New York, NY, USA; Ithaca, NY, USA, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - a. S b. information requests, anthropometric study, public health program, anthropology and public health, nutrition studies, project supplies acquisition, comparative studies program organization, data processing, classification system, Vicos book outline, anthropology society activities c. Blanchard, William C.; Collazos Chiriboga, Carlos; Lube, Cato; Putnam, Emilie B.; Chaparro, Yolanda; Smith, Robert J.; Snyder, Joan e. Servicio Cooperativo Inter-Americano de Salud Publica, Servicio Cooperativo Inter-Americano de Produccion de Alimentos, Foreign Operations Administration Institute of Inter-American Affairs, Sociedad para Antropologia Peruana, Cornell Peru Project f. correspondence, telegrams, reports g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; Ithaca, NY, USA, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - a. T, U, V, W b. visitors to Vicos, project supplies acquisition, personnel arrangements, project archives control, field director responsibilities, classification system, medical survey, public health studies c. Temple, Charles R.; Valcarcel, Luis E.; Blanchard, William C.; Vazquez D., Carlos A.; Vazquez, Mario C.; Villalobos, Enrique; Von Hagen, Victor e. Touring y Automovil Club del Peru, UNICEF, Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos, Dean of Ithaca, Inc., Cornell Peru Project f. correspondence, telegrams, reports, memoranda g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru; Ithaca, NY, USA, 1953-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Financial Accounts and Labor Records
      This final section consists of financial accounts and labor records of the CPP. The records of hacienda expenditures, the school construction account, and records of seed and produce sales are notable for showing how work on the hacienda was organized. These records are in bound volumes and cover the years 1952-1956.
      - a. Ingreso Huertas b. hacienda produce account f. bound notebook g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1956 (Box 23)
      - a. Ventas b. produce prices--Vicosinos, produce prices-outsiders, produce purchase accounts of Vicosinos f. bound notebooks (2) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1956 (Box 23)
      - a. Construccion Local Escuela b. materials expenses, laborers weekly records, school construction f. bound notebooks (3) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1955 (Box 23)
      - a. Hacienda accounts and Labor Records (volumes 1-4) b. seed purchases, laborers daily employment, produce purchase--hacienda, produce sales to Vicosinos, produce sales to outsiders f. bound notebooks (12 total) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1953 (Box 23)
      - a. Hacienda accounts and Labor Records (volumes 5-12) b. seed purchases, laborers daily employment, produce purchase--hacienda, produce sales to Vicosinos, produce sales to outsiders f. bound notebooks (12 total) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1953-1956 (Box 24)
      - a. Diario I b. monthly produce chart, monthly income and expenses chart, hacienda daily expenditures f. charts, bound journal (financial) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1953 (Box 8)
      - Produce charts from Diario I (Mapcase-folder 6)
      - a. Planilla de Salarios b. salaries hacienda personnel f. bound journal (financial) g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1952-1955 (Box 8)
      - a. Diario II b. school construction, hacienda receipts and disbursements, seed purchases--Vicosinos, Diario I totals g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1956; 1 bound journal, 1 folder (Box 8)
  - Field Data
    The CPP field data includes notes from field observations by members of the CPP, as well as data from various censuses, surveys, studies, and activities of the CPP. The field data was collected during studies ranging in date from 1946 t o 1965. There are notes from field observations in Marcara, Vicos and Viru made before the start of the CPP by individuals subsequently involved with the project. The basic arrangement consists of five sections which correspond to the major types of data in the series.
    - Field Notebooks
      Section one contains field note books kept by members of the CPP. Humberto Ghersi Barrera's notebooks on Marcara, and some by Allan R. Holmberg and Mario C. Vazquez predate the start of the official project. The field notebooks contain notes dated from 1948 to 1954, the early years of the project. This is the only ethnographic data in the collection, except for that contained in the HRAF (Human Relations Area Files).
      - Allan R. Holmberg b. project supplies, labor payments, slide identification, Quechua terms, daily routine, ethnographic descriptions g. Callejon de Huaylas, Peru; Vicos, Ancash, Peru; Lima, Peru, 1948-1953, 1960; 11 notebooks (Box 3)
      - Joan Snyder b. accommodations arrangements, ethnographic descriptions, daily routine g. Recuayhuanca, Ancash, Peru, 1951-1952; 11 notebooks (Box 4)
      - Humberto Ghersi Barrera, Notebooks contain information on personal expenses, ethnographic descriptions, daily routine, and Quechua terms. Marcara, Ancash, Peru.
        - Libreta de Gastos, 1949-1950; 1 notebook (Box 25)
        - Field notebooks I-X., March-June 1949; 10 notebooks, 1 envelope (Box 25)
        - Field notebooks XI-XXI., June-July 1949; 11 notebooks (Box 26)
        - Field notebooks Series II. XXII-XXIX, Series III. XXX-XXXIII., 1949-1950; 12 notebooks (Box 27)
        - Field notebooks Series III. XXXIV-XXXIX, Series IV. XL-XLIII, Series V. XLIV-XLV; vocabulario de Quechua, 1950; 12 notebooks, 1 envelope (Box 28)
        - Field notebooks Series V. XLVI-XLVII, [no series] 48-59, 1950-1951; 14 notebooks (Box 29)
        - Field notebooks 60-73, 71 [74]-72 [75], 1951; 16 notebooks (Box 35)
        - Field notebooks 73 [76]-76 [79], 77 [79] Censo del Distrito de Marcara, 1951-1952; 5 notebooks, 1 folder, 1 envelope (Box 36)
      - Mario C. Vazquez, Notebooks contain information on personal expenses, ethnographic descriptions, daily routine, mayorales meetings, and an agricultural innovation sanitation survey. Vicos, Ancash, Peru.
        - Field notebooks I-VI, April-June 1949; 6 notebooks (Box 36)
        - Field notebooks VII-IX, XI, XIII-XVII, June 1949-January 1950; 9 notebooks (Box 37)
        - Relacion de gastos: Informantes y otros, April 1949; 1 notebook (Box 37)
        - Field notebooks XVIII-XXIII, January-March 1950; 6 notebooks, 1 folder (Box 38)
        - Field notebook, September 1949-March 1950; 1 notebook (Box 38)
        - Field notebooks I, [no number], June 1951-January 1952; 2 notebooks (Box 38)
        - Field notebooks I-V, January 1952-October 1953; 5 notebooks (Box 39)
        - Reunion mayorales y mandos, August 1952-April 1954; 1 notebook (Box 39)
        - Survey sanitario, March-April 1954; 1 notebook (Box 39)
        - Maiz cusqueno, 1953-1954; 1 notebook (Box 39)
        - [Inscripcion] siembra papas, 1954; 1 notebook (Box 39)
      - Jorge [Laundio or Laumdio?] R. - field notebook - anexo XIa., September-October 1949; 1 notebook (Box 37)
      - Robert Farrier-vocabulary notebook, undated (Box 24)
    - Environmental and Land Tenure Data
      Section two contains environmental and land tenure data. A photographic study of land tenure was made in 1955 to show the division of cultivated plots, or chacras, on Hacienda Vicos. Charts and photographs from the study are in this subseries. Environmental data include a daily temperature record kept in 1954-1955, and topographic and hydrological charts from 1963.
      - a. Estudios de los terrenos de Vicos b. land tenure, geographical features f. photographs, maps, outline g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1955 (Box 14)
        Folder contains original photograph "Aerial photo of land plots in Vicos - Plano 5," Digital Image ID RMC2004_5365
      - a. Vicos Maps and Hydrologic Data b. topography, water balance c. Vescelius, Gary S.; Basurto, B. e. Cornell Peru Project Archeological Program f. maps, charts g. Callejon de Huaylas, Peru, 1963 (Box 14)
      - a. Temperature Record b. daily temperature range, meteorological remarks f. bound notebook g. Vicos, Ancash, Peru, 1954-1955 (Box 24)
    - HRAF notes and other field notes
      The HRAF notes are in section three. The notes were copied onto 8" x 5" paper and categorized according to the HRAF system. Allan R. Holmberg's field notes from Viru are the earliest material in the collection, dating from 1946. Besides the large section of notes on Vicos, there are notes from field work done in Viru, Marcara, Paucartambo, Recuayhuanca, Huaylas and Moche. The files also contain a section of hacienda records, consisting of field accounts, peon work records, and work records for other individuals who held special positions in the hacienda work force. There are three separate files of field notes on Vicos, one that was kept in Vicos, one in Lima, and one in Ithaca. The Ithaca file is by far the largest, and theoretically contains duplicates of notes in the other two files, but duplication is spotty. Additional sorting and filing has been limited to the Ithaca file and there are some notes yet to be sorted and filed. Anyone using the files should be aware that many notes have been over-categorized, which expands quantity, but detracts from substance for the categories. A manual, Outline of Cultural Material, in Box 11 lists the subjects in each category and tells how to use the files.
      - Outline of Cultural Material, 4th revised edition (guide book for HRAF classification) (Box 11, Folder 38)
      - Field notes (continued in box 42) (Box 40)
      - Field notes; census cards; small notebook (Box 41)
      - Field notes (Box 42)
      - Prof. Allan Holmberg - Viru #101-349 (Box 43)
      - Prof. Allan Holmberg - Viru #351-516, field notes (Box 44)
      - Prof. Allan Holmberg - Viru field notes, census (Box 45)
      - Prof. Allan Holmberg - Viru field notes; Humberto Ghersi B. - Marcara #101-346 (Box 46)
      - Humberto Ghersi B. - Marcara #349-794 (Box 47)
      - Humberto Ghersi B. - Marcara #796-874 and mixed, field notes; Paucartambo field notes, #56-117 (Box 48)
      - Paucartambo #117-632 (Box 49)
      - Paucartambo #634-883, field notes (Box 50)
      - Paucartambo field notes; Hickman - field notes; Recuayhuanca field notes, #117-292; Paul Doughty - Huaylas field notes (Box 51)
      - Paul Doughty - Huaylas field notes, Vicos; Huaraz (Box 52)
      - Vicos-names and zones 1952; CPP mailing list (Box 53)
      - CPP mailing list; Edward Epstein - Moche field notes; Stephen Most - Moche field notes; Leo Levy - Huanchaco field notes; Vicos field notes to file in Ithaca file (Box 54)
      - Vicos field notes to sort (Box 55)
      - Vicos field notes to sort (File-drawer 4B)
      - Vicos field notes to sort (File-drawer 5A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #101-564 (Lima-Vicos file) (File-drawer 6A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #565-888, personnel (Lima-Vicos file) (File-drawer 7A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #101-158 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 8A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #159-personnel, #162-239 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 9A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #240-417 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 10A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #421-567 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 11A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #570-627 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 12A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #631-779 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 13A & B)
      - Vicos field notes #781-888 (Ithaca-Vicos file) (File-drawer 14A & B)
    - Censuses and Surveys
      Section four contains censuses and surveys taken during the CPP. The data sheets for all censuses are complete, and are organized by zones in Vicos. Aside from the censuses, there are data sheets for a land tenure survey and socio-economic status ratings. Censuses were taken in 1951, 1957, 1959, 1969, and 1963. For data on the New Seed Potato experiment see the analysis sheets in Subseries I - Administrative Materials. Other questionnaires and code designs are also in Subseries I - Administrative Materials.
      - a. Vicos Anthropological Census f. census forms, 1951 (Box 5)
      - a. Aquia Census M. C. Vazquez f. print-outs (Box 14)
      - a. Vicos Census b. by subzones f. census forms, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16-23)
      - a. Vicos Land Tenure Survey f. survey forms, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
      - a. Vicos Census b. by subzones f. census forms, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1-8)
      - a. Vicos Census b. by sub zones f. census forms, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 9-16)
      - a. Vicos Census b. by subzones f. census forms, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 1-10)
      - a. Vicos Census Analysis SES b. socio-economic status ratings f. lists, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Census tallies (by subzone), undated (Box 14)
      - a. Questionnaire Alers b. economic development, inhabitants of Vicos, heads of Vicos families c. Alers, J. Oscar f. questionnaires, lists, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Vicos communication survey-preliminary draft, J. Oscar Alers, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - a. Vicos Innovation Alers b. innovation acceptance, modernization c. Alers, J. Oscar f. report, note, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Health Clinic Records
      The fifth section contains records from the Vicos health clinic. They are wall charts used to keep track of patient and staff attendance for 1954-1955.
      - a. Asistencia de los enfermos a la clinica A-V Enero-Diciembre b. clinic patients attendance record f. charts, 1954? (Mapcase-folder 2)
      - a. Ano 1954, Julio-Diciembre A-V Clinic Personnel b. clinic personnel attendance record, clinic patients attendance record f. charts (Mapcase-folder 3)
      - a. Ano 1955 Enero-Diciembre A-V b. clinic patients attendance record f. charts (Mapcase-folder 4)
  - Reprints, Publications and Papers
    Subseries three contains printed materials written between 1952 and 1966 (there is one paper written in 1972). The authors are generally people connected with the CPP, the Columbia-Cornell-Harvard Summer Field Studies Program, or the IIP, although there are popular descriptions and reports by individuals not connnected with these organizations. The bibliography is arranged alphabetically by author. Entries are numbered sequentially to correspond to the numbers used in The Cornell Peru Project Bibliography and Personnel (Dobyns and Vazquez, 1964). When the collection was accessioned some printed materials had been arranged by this system. There was also a sizable number of papers or publications not included in the bibliography, which had no arrangement, but that have been incorporated into this subseries. Material from the first accession fitting one of the three section headings of the bibliography was numbered sequentially and placed at the end of the appropriate section. Publications from the second accession were incorporated into the bibliography where appropriate but they were not numbered. The titles of the sections are: Administrative Proposals, Reports and Documents; Cornell Peru Project Scientific Reports; and Popular Descriptions of the Cornell Peru Project. Two other sections were established for material that did not fit the original three. The two new sections are: Cornell Comparative Studies of Cultural Change Scientific Reports; and Andean Indian Community Research and Development Program Scientific Reports. Some of the papers in Sections IV and V are based on information gathered as part of the CPP, but not produced as CPP publications.
    - Administrative Proposals, Reports and Documents
      - 1. Adams, Richard N.; and Cumberland, Charles C. United States University Cooperation in Latin America. East Lansing: Institute of Research on Overseas Programs, Michigan State University. (The Peru-Cornell Anthropology Project of Cornell University and the Instituto Indigenista Peruano, pp. 187-196)., 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - 3. Blanchard, William C. "Tercer Informe del Proyecto Peru-Cornell," Peru Indigena, V: 12 pp. 153-159., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - 4. Blanchard, William C. "Informe del Proyecto Peru-Cornell: 1954," Boletin Indigenista, XV: 3 (Sept.) 274-285., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - 5. Blanchard, William C. "Informe del Proyecto Peru-Cornell: 1955," Boletin Indigenista, XVI: 2-3 (Aqosto) 202-215., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - 7. Dobyns, Henry F. "El Proyecto Peru Cornell," Peru Indigena, IX: 20-21 (Enero-Junio) 125-130., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - 8. Dobyns, Henry F. Eleventh Report of the Cornell Peru Project., 1962 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - 9. Dobyns, Henry F.; and Monge M., Carlos. "20 Aniversario de la Sociedad de Antropologia Aplicada," Peru Indigena, IX: 20-21 (Enero-Junio) 141-143., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Doughty, Paul L.; and Vazquez, Mario C. Duodecimo Informe del Proyecto Peru-Cornell., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - 10. Holmberg, Allan R. "La Realizacion del Proyecto de Antropologia Aplicada en la Zona de Vicos, Marcara, Ancash," Peru Indigena, 11: 4 (Enero) 88-90., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - 11. Holmberg, Allan R. "Estudios de Aculturacion en el Callejon de Huaylas," Peru Indigena, 11: 4 (Enero) 91-95., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - 13. "Proyecto Peru-Cornell en las Ciencias Sociales Aplicadas," Peru Indigena, 11: 5-6 (Junio) 158-166., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - 17. Holmberg, Allan R.; and Monge M., Carlos "Prorroga del acuerdo Celebrado entre la Universidad de Cornell y el Instituto Indigenista Peruano," Boletin Indigenista. XVII: 4 (Dic.) 358-363., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - 30. Vazquez, Mario C.; and Dobyns, Henry F. Summary Description of Vicos School Lunch Program. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph)., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - 31. Velasco Nunez, Manuel D. "Proyecto Peru-Cornell," Boletin Indigenista, XV: 1 (Marzo) 78-79., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - 32. Velasco Nunez, Manuel D. "Informe del Instituto Indigenista Peruano: 1955," Boletin Indigenista, XVI: 1 (Marzo) 84-95., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Bibliografia del Proyecto Peru-Cornell de 1951 a 1964. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - The Vicos Research Proposal, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - I.1. Alers, J. Oscar; Vazquez, Mario C.; Holmberg, Allan R.; and Dobyns, Henry F. Human Freedom and Geographic Mobility. Ithaca: Cornell University Department of Anthropology (mimeograph). also in Current, 6:3 (June) 336. 1965. (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - I.2. Dobyns, Henry F.; and Vazquez, Mario C. a. The Cornell Peru Project Bibliography and Personnel. Ithaca: Cornell Peru Project Pamphlet No. 2, Department of Anthropology. 1964. b. Bibliografia del Proyecto Peru-Cornell entre el 1 de Diciembre de 1963 y el 30 de Noviembre de 1964. (copy) c. Bibliography of the Cornell-Peru Project. (mimeograph). Oct., 1959 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - I.3. Holmberg, Allan R.; and Dobyns, Henry F. "Transformation of Peasant Societies," Science, 147:3661 (Feb.) 1062-1066. 1965. (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - I.4. Morris, Earl W. Etapas para el Desarrollo Socio-Economico de Mayobamba. Lima: Folletos del Proyecto Peru-Cornell No. 3. 1964. (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - I.5. Social Science Research Center. Reactions in Peru to the Cornell Peru Project. Ithaca: Cornell University (mimeograph). 1959. (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Turner, Frank L. Benchmarks to Measure Economic Progress in a Peruvian Village. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Cornell Peru Project Scientific Reports
      - 33. Allen, Fred H., Jr. "Inheritance of the Diego (Dia) Blood-Group Factor," American Journal of Human Genetics, 10:l (March) 64-67., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - 34. Andrews, David H. "Migration en Paucartambo, Pasco, Peru," Migracion e integracion en el Peru. editores: Henry F. Dobyns y Mario C. Vazquez. Lima, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - Andrews, David H. "Public Image of President John F. Kennedy in Paucartambo, Peru." (Box 1, Folder 63)
      - 35. Andrews, David H. Integration in a Peruvian Indigenous Community. paper read before 60th Annual Meeting, American Anthropological Association, Philadelphia, Nov. 16, 1961. (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - 37. Arellano Bados, Consuelo. Opinion Publica y Comunicacion en la Provincia de Tam. Lima: Proyecto Peru-Cornell (mimeograph). 1962. (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - 38. Barkin, David. Commercial Activity in a Peruvian Community. N.Y.: Columbia University (mimeograph) 1961. (Box 1, Folder 66)
      - 41. Bradfield, Stillman. Migration from Huaylas: A Study of Brothers. Cornell University Ph.D. Thesis. 1963., 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - 43. Castillo Ardiles, Hernan. Migracion Interna en el Peru: Una Bibliografia. Lima: Universidad de San Marcos. 1961. (mimeograph) (Box 1, Folder 68)